Greetings, and today is one of those LGR things where we don’t ask “why,” but instead ask
大家好，本期LGR视频，我们不讲原理知识，而是尝试些奇怪的东西
“why not.” Cuz we’re gonna be loading a PC game from quarter-inch reel to reel audio tape,
本期视频，我们将从0.25英寸的开盘带上加载电脑游戏
simply for fun because we can. All we’ll need is a tape recorder, some blank tape, a suitable
这纯粹是做着玩啦。只需一个录音机，一些空白磁带，一根合适的
audio cable, and a computer capable of playing and recording 8-bit PCM audio in mono at 22 kilohertz.
内录线，还有一台能录制播放22kHz，8位单声道PCM音频的电脑
Now, obviously there’s no practical reason to do this, and if you’re familiar with 1980s
当然，现在这么做并没有什么意义，但如果你对上世纪80年代的
microcomputers then you already know they can load programs from tape. Being a cheaper alternative
微型计算机有所了解的话，那你对从磁带上加载软件这件事就不陌生了
注：此处的“微型计算机”指的是上世纪70年代生产的个人电脑。
相对于当时的大型机，体积小多了。例如Commodore 64，小霸王之类的。
to floppy disks, dozens of classic computers were designed to use audio cassette tapes as
由于这样加载软件比软盘便宜，当时有很多电脑将从磁带加载软件当作
their primary method of loading and saving data. Even the original IBM PC had a cassette port,
加载或保存软件的首要方式，甚至于原版的IBM电脑都有一个磁带接口
so loading personal computer software from cassette is nothing new. Or even vinyl, there have
所以说，从磁带加载软件并不是什么新鲜事。甚至黑胶唱片也可以呢
been a number of flexi disc and other records released containing KCS-encoded data in audio
当时有很多的软件被用KCS编码转变成声音，然后录在
form. But using reel to reel tape? Now that’s even more exciting, being a costlier enthusiast
软唱片之类的介质上。但要用开盘带的话，就更有意思了
format that no home computer user would bother wasting for data storage back in the day. Business
这玩意可贵了，在当时没有任何家用电脑用这个介质存数据
and government mainframes, sure, those often used tape drives with reels housing half inch tape. But
不过政商界用的大型机常使用盘式录音机，上面挂的是半英寸的开盘带
the way those wrote data isn’t quite what we’re doing today, despite some aesthetic similarities.
尽管方式有相同之处，不过这回我不介绍往磁带写数据的原理了
Instead we’re gonna be recording and retrieving data using a variant of the Kansas City Standard.
这里，我们要用一种变种标准，KCS标准来处理数据
Also known as Byte Standard, KCS was a recording method designed for early personal
KCS标准也称Byte标准，于1975年发布
computers to store data on compact cassette tapes, a standard first introduced in 1975.
用来在早期个人电脑上，将数据录制到磁带上
Speaking of 1975, that’s also when this tape deck was made! This is a Tandberg 10XD,
说到1975年，我有一台当年生产的开盘机，这就是Tandberg 10XD
which I’m using not only because it’s also from 1975, but also because it’s a machine that can
我要用这台机器进行实验，不仅仅是因为这是1975年生产的
record to 10.5-inch reels at a transport speed of 15 inches per second. So it looks great on
而且这可以以15英寸每秒的速度，将声音录到半径10.5英寸的开盘带上
camera with those huge metal reels, and it’ll sound great too, with 15 ips being way better
这样在摄像机上，超大的金属圆盘看上去很耐人，而且
than the Kansas City Standard was ever intended to use. For reference, typical cassette tapes have a
15英寸每秒的录制速度已经超过KCS标准要求了。按照标准，
transport speed of just 1⅞ inches per second, so having 15 ips at our disposal should be fantastic
普通的磁带转速为1.875英寸每秒，所以用15英寸每秒的转速
for reliable data storage. On that note, the media I’m using is a brand new 2500ft reel of Recording
存数据就更好了。在这点上，我要用一个2500英尺长的
the Masters SM911 quarter-inch tape. It’s a nice 1.97 mil, high output, low noise tape that sounds
全新四分之一英寸宽的磁带，厚度0.05mm，底噪很小，输出很强
注：mil是长度单位，1mil=0.0254mm
excellent with music and sound recordings, so it should be absolute overkill for storing data.
特别适合用来播放音乐和录音，所以用来存数据的话，完全是大材小用
Just gotta string it through the tape path and get it queued up here, and we’re pretty much ready
只需将磁带固定于此，并穿过下面，就差不多OK了
to go on the tape side of things. On the computer side, I’m going with the LGR Megaluminum Monster,
在电脑方面，我要用这台LGR大块头机器
注：BV1E7411h7o5  Megaluminum Monster评测 @ LGR & wu_dl
which is a Windows 98 PC with a 1 gigahertz Pentium III and 512 megs of RAM. See my build
预装Windows 98，内置1Ghz奔腾III处理器和512M内存
video for more details on that, but the main thing that matters is the sound card. And I’ve
想看的话看上方注释，但这回更重要的是声卡
got a couple of them installed here, but for this project I’m using the Creative Sound Blaster AWE64
我这台电脑装了两张声卡，这里我要用创新的声卡
Gold. The RCA output plugs directly into the reel to reel’s line in, and output of the reel to reel
莲花头一端接入开盘机输入接口，另一端接到声卡的
goes to the line in on the sound card. With a quick stop in the middle to plug in some speakers
输出接口，在中间串联一个扬声器
so we can actually hear what we’re doing. And by the way, magnetic weirdness is always
这样我们就可以监听了。还有，对于磁带来说
a concern with tape, but what’s going on here is fine. Those little speakers are magnetically
磁铁是需要注意的，但是这回还行，扬声器里面已经给
shielded and I don’t have the reel to reel right up against them or the monitor anyway, so yeah.
磁屏蔽了，我也没有将开盘机正放在扬声器或是大屁股前面
The bigger concern is getting a clean audio signal between the computer and the reel to reel,
在这个过程中，最应该注意的是如何传输干净的声音信号
and my biggest worry was that the AWE64’s line in recording might be too noisy. The only way to
我最担心的是声卡的声音输出可能杂音很大
know for sure is to give it a test, so let’s hop into a DOS prompt and run KCS08. This is a program
所以我要测试一下。我现在要在DOS命令行下运行KCS08
that handles Kansas City Standard cassette recordings, where you can take any file and
这个程序可以将数据用KCS标准编码成声音
encode it as audio, and also decode KCS audio and convert it to data. Even though it was designed
当然，也可以将KCS标准处理过的声音解码成数据
for cassette tapes, there’s no reason it shouldn’t work on reel to reel. Just as a quick test though,
尽管这是为磁带设计的，但在开盘机上也能工作，现在简单测试一下
I typed up a small document in MS-DOS Edit and saved it as a TXT file. Then it’s onto KCS08,
我在MS-DOS Edit编辑器下写了一个TXT文档，然后使用KCSO8软件
with the command for encoding being “KCS -U -M -Y”.
输入如图命令  （翻译Syu去了）
This makes a WAV file, ignores errors, and enables 1200 baud mode.
然后生成了一个WAV文件，忽略解码错误，并启动了1200波特模式
注：波特是调制速率单位，暂且认为 1baud=1bps
KCS normally encodes at 300 baud, or 300 bits per second, but that results
一般KCS标准的解码速度是300波特，也就是300bit每秒
in recordings four times as long, so, screw that. And yep, that’s it! We’ve now got a WAV
但要这样的话，录音时长就得长4倍了，还是算了吧
file that’s eleven seconds long storing our test text file in audio form, which sounds like this.
好了，我们生成了一个11秒长的音频，里面存着数据，听起来像这样
This works in a similar way to serial modems,
有点像当时的拨号上网
where each binary bit of information is stored using audio frequency shift keying, or AFSK.
每一位数据都以声频移频键控方式存储，缩写为AFSK
注：以数字信号控制载波频率变化的调制方式，称为频移键控
Basically lots of 1s and 0s represented by really short sine wave cycles in quick succession.
基本上每一位数据都转换成了很短的的正弦波，变化频率很快
And now we can play it back and record it to tape. Cool Edit 96 is my audio program of choice here,
现在我们可以播放并录制到磁带上了，这里我用Cool Edit 96
SuperBart：Cool Edit 就是现在 Adobe Audition 的前身
我在初中机房里见过，不过没有什么印象
since I’ve used it for decades and I know it does exactly what I need. You could just as
因为我用这个软件有几十年了，功能对我而言够用了
easily use a DOS audio program and do this whole process on an even older computer if you wanted,
在老DOS电脑上使用十分容易，而且还可以在更老的电脑上使用
but I’ve got Windows 98 on here so why not. Just gotta make sure it’s playing back as
但我已经有一台Windows 98了，所以就用更好的吧。电脑那边的
loud as possible on the computer side, and not completely blowing things out on the tape side.
回放越响越好，而且磁带录音方面也不要破音
I’m also not using any noise reduction, we’re simply goin’ in raw.
我也没用任何降噪处理，基本就是原样输出
After a couple of volume checks, it’s time to record some data!
再三检查音量后，该录些数据了:-)
Sweet! We now have a file on tape, and getting it back on the PC is as simple as re-recording our
好极了，我在磁带上已经录上了数据，将其录回电脑和
recording with the same parameters KCS expects. Which is an 8-bit WAV file in mono at 22kHz. This
重新录音没什么两样，都是KCS标准的8位22kHz单声道音频文件
version of Cool Edit isn’t set to display the waveform as it’s recording, but once it’s done,
这个版本的Cool Edit在录音的时候不会显示波形图
there we go! We’ve got a recording of a recorded recording. Nice. Just gonna trim the file to
但没什么问题，我们把录进去的东西又录了回来，把开头
remove the sections without audio, save that, go back to KCS, and now we can decode it back
结尾的空白位置去掉，再用KCS处理一下就行了，这样我就
to a text file. The command is about the same but in reverse, going from WAV to TXT. Didn’t
解码出文本文件了，命令基本一致，但是wav和txt换了一下位置
get any decode errors, so that’s promising. And would ya look at that? A text file saved in DOS,
没有解码错误，看上去应该行。现在再看看这个文本文件
recorded to tape, played back, and loaded back in DOS again! The only bit of weirdness is this
DOS下保存，录到磁带中，再录制回来，又加载回DOS了！
random block at the beginning of the text file, that wasn’t there before. I went back
唯一不同之处在于文本开头的方块，一开始是没有的
and re-trimmed the recording and adjusted the volume a bit to see if that made a difference,
我回去重新去掉了空白位置，调整一下音量，看看有什么不同
but nope. Still got a random block of text at the beginning of the file either way. I’m not sure
但是并没有，在文本开头仍然看到了方块。我也搞不清
what that’s about, or what it means for storing a whole program. Only one way to find out though,
到底是啥情况，或是对存取数据来说有什么意义。不过只有实践出真知
so let’s go back, rewind to a good spot, and record a full PC game on reel to reel tape!
那咱就从头再来，磁带倒回一个好位置，再将游戏录到磁带上:-)
So, my immediate choice for a game to record was Doom. Because of course, who wouldn’t wanna load
我一开始想把DOOM录到磁带上，从开盘带上加载
Doom from a big ol’ 10-inch tape machine? Problem is, encoding Doom to KCS results in a ridiculous
DOOM一定很酷的。可惜，将DOOM用KCS编码后，音频太长了
5 hour, 24 minute WAV file, even at the faster 1200 baud. And that’s the two megabyte
5小时24分的音频文件，就是用较快的1200波特编码，那也是200MB啊
compressed shareware version of Doom, not even the full game, so both are outta the question.
这还是试玩版DOOM，不是完整版，所以就算了吧:-(
Even if we weren’t recording at 15 inches per second and went all the way down to 3 ¾, that’d
而且就算我们不以15英寸每秒，而是3.75英寸每秒的速度走带
still only get us around 133 minutes per direction on our 2500ft reel. So we’ve gotta think smaller,
每面磁带也只有133分钟的录音时长，所以，我们得找个大小
way smaller, in terms of game size. And because I don’t wanna be here all week I’ve chosen to encode
小得多的游戏。鉴于我不想整周都在搞这个
Kingdom of Kroz by Apogee Software. For one, it’s only 52.4 kilobytes, and for two,
我直接用这个游戏了。首先，游戏大小仅52.4KB
the entire game is packed into a single executable. I didn’t wanna record multiple
其次，整个游戏只有一个可执行文件。我可不想录制多个文件
files or compress things into a ZIP if I could help it, so this works nicely. And using the
或是压缩好再录。当然，过程一切顺利，使用原先的KCS设定
same KCS settings as earlier, our 52K game has resulted in an 8 minute, 12 second WAV file. Heh,
的话，整个52KB的游戏就被编码成8分12秒的波形文件了
yeah. 53,707 bytes loading at 1200 bits per second, whatcha gonna do? And for ease of use
没办法，1200bps的速度编码53,707字节，真的没办法:-(
I made some batch files to make the encoding and decoding a one-click process under Windows
为了方便，我写了一个脚本，以让在资源浏览器下
Explorer. And yeah, at this point it’s just the same thing we did earlier, but 8 minutes longer
编解码文件能一键完成。现在的步骤和一开始差不多，只不过每一步
each way! Again, I really wasn’t sure how well this would work since 8 minutes is plenty of
都要比之前还要长8分钟啊！当然，我不知道最后会如何，因为
time for errors to crop up, either introduced on the PC side of things or the reel to reel side.
这么长时间内不管是在电脑端，还是在录音端，绝对会产生错误
I mean, Windows 98 PCs and Creative Sound Blasters aren’t exactly known for their noise-free audio,
毕竟家用电脑和这张声卡可不是无底噪的啊
and the Tandberg 10XD may be in good shape but it’s still 46 years old so you just never know.
还有这台开盘机，虽然品相不错，但这可是46年前生产的啊
That being said, the recording process went just fine so all that’s left to do now is to rewind it,
话虽这么说，录音过程很顺利，剩下的事就是倒完带
record it back to the PC, and see how it goes! I adjusted the input volume beforehand this time
录回电脑了，然后看看情况如何吧。我在播放前将输入端的
so the resulting WAV file was maxed out, making it look even more similar to the original output
音量开到最大，最终的音频文件很响亮，和原先的音频文件
from KCS. Now for the decoding, which only takes a couple seconds thankfully. And check it
基本一样。之后的编码过程仅需几秒，现在该验收了:-)
out! 53,708 bytes decoded with 1 decode error. If you’ll remember, the original Kroz file was 53,707
成功解码53,708比特，有1次编码出错。原先文件大小是53707
bytes, so we’ve picked up a stowaway somewhere along the line. But whatever let’s run it anyway.
所以中间一定是多解码了一位。无论如何，赶紧运行一下
-Oh my goodness.
╰(*°▽°*)╯
Aha man, it worked! Despite the extra byte latched
天哪，就算某处多出了一位，它还能运行啊！
on somewhere, I can’t see anything wrong with the game at all. I assume that there’s
看上去游戏运行基本正常诶
我觉得和一开始测试的的文本一样，某处又出现了
something similar going on to the text file we tested, where there's just an additional
weird character tossed in there somewhere. And like, I can’t imagine that’s a good thing right?
一些奇怪的数据。而且这也肯定不是什么好事吧
But it certainly doesn’t seem to have affected the game at all. It runs, plays, looks, and sounds
不过这个游戏没有受到影响，一切都是本应该的样子
as it should. [chuckles] Fantastic stuff. PC games on reel to reel tape, what in the world.
天哪，我真的把游戏录到开盘带上了，真是好神奇哦
Granted, at this speed the maximum size we could fit is only 230 kilobytes per direction, at least
当然，按照15英寸每秒的走带速度的话，一面只能存储230KB的数据
at a tape speed of 15 ips. Now obviously you can store more data at slower speeds and use longer
当然，你也可以通过减慢走带速度，或是使用长些的磁带来
tapes, but it’d be supremely cumbersome, with more room for error and truly ridiculous loading times.
存储更多数据，不过受累不讨好，加载时间长，出错概率大
And you could also use a terminal program instead of KCS08 and load data more directly from
你也可以用某些终端软件来直接加载数据
tape instead of converting recordings back and forth. And there’s nothing stopping you from
而不是使用KCSO8编码后录过去再录回来。你在现代电脑上
doing all this on a modern system either, it’s all just binary data moving over audio cables,
也可以这么做，就是将数据通过音频线传输罢了
so as long as you’ve got some way to convert from one to the other then hey, go wild. But that’s
所以说，你有能力，你就放开做吧:-)
starting to enter the areas of practicality and halfway reasonable usage. And suffice it to say
不过这就开始有点实用性了，差不多可以日常使用了
but this video was by no means intended to show anything practical or reasonable. This was simply
不过说真的，这个视频并不是给大家介绍任何有实际意义的东西
an LGR thing for a bit of fun, and one example of something that can be done with old data storage
我就是图个开心罢了。但你可以用过时的数据存储标准和
standards using equally old tape recorders. Making PC game tapes is admittedly not why I got into
差不多一样旧的磁带录音机来存储数据啊。我又不是为了
reel to reel equipment after all. It’s much more about playing back hours of high quality analog
录制游戏磁带而买的开盘机啊。开盘机在以前是用来
music on tape and experimenting with multitrack recording and all that stuff. So I’m gonna go
播放很长的高品质音乐，或是多轨混音啥的
ahead and hook it back up to the main stereo now. But I hope that you enjoyed seeing this bit of
所以我还是将其放回我的音响系统吧:-P不过希望大家
computery silliness anyway. And perhaps give it a try if you’ve got an old tape deck lying around,
喜欢看这些老掉牙的技术，如果你也有磁带机的话，你也可以试试
reel to reel or otherwise. For the time being, I can think of no better way to
当然，开盘机也行啦。现在呢，我还是播放
end this than leaving you with a direct 15 ips reel to reel recording of canyon.mid.
录制到开盘磁带上的canyon.mid来结束本期视频吧
翻译：SuperBart@Bilibili
校对：Citrusnyade@Bilibili
原作者LGR发布于2021年3月12日
翻译仓促，请多谅解，请多多请教
感谢收看！